A Guide to the Cary Reich papers FA1275
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Oral History Audio, circa 1980s (Bulk: 1982); 2
  - H-K, 2.4
    - Koch, Edward, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9600)
      Interview. Koch was a three-term Democratic mayor of New York from 1978 to 1989 who earlier served as a member of the U.S. House of Representatives, 1969 to 1977. Koch interview ends at 23 minutes. Tape then contains partial interview with Albert and Viginia Callan. Albert Callan was a Columbia County (New York) Republican leader, and Virginia Callan was a gubernatorial aide to Nelson Rockefeller.
    - Kresky, Edward - Part 1, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9601)
      Interview. Kresky was a gubernatorial aide to Nelson Rockefeller.
    - Kresky, Edward - Part 2, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9602A)
      Interview. Kresky was a gubernatorial aide to Nelson Rockefeller. Kresky interview ends at 100 minutes, 6 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Jacob Underhill until 179 minutes, 8 seconds. Underhill was assistant press secretary to Governor Nelson Rockefeller and later deputy superintendent and then first deputy superintendent of insurance for the State of New York, 1968-1972. Tape then continues with interview with Kresky until end.
    - Kresky, Edward - Part 3, circa 1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9602B)
      Interview. Kresky was a gubernatorial aide to Nelson Rockefeller. Kresky interview ends at 226 minutes, 40 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with New York State Assemblymen Alfred Lerner and Joseph Kunzeman until end.
    - Kresky, Mary M., circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9603)
      Interview. Kresky was an associate of Nelson Rockefeller, worked in his personal office at the Rockefeller Family Office in Manhattan.
    - Kuhnen, Richard, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9604)
      Interview. Kuhnen was Republican chair from Broome County, New York.
  - L-M, 2.5
    - Lanford, Oscar, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9605)
      Interview. Lanford was the president of the SUNY Fredonia.
    - Lanigan, Charles, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9606)
      Interview. Lanigan was New York state Republican chair in the 1960s.
    - Lankler, Alexander, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9607)
      Interview. Lankler was a campaign aide for Governor Nelson Rockefeller.
    - Lathrop, Churchill, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9608)
      Interview. Professor of art history at Dartmouth College while Nelson Rockefeller was an undergraduate. He went on to collaborate with Nelson and Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, co-founder of the Museum of Modern Art, to develop the modern art collection at Dartmouth.
    - LaVerne, Thomas, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9609)
      Interview. LaVerne was a Republican New York State senator, 1961-1972.
    - Lawrence, Richard, circa 1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9610)
      Interview. Lawrence worked on the Temporary Study Commission on the Future of the Adirondacks and later was appointed by Governor Rockefeller as the first chair of the Adirondack Park Agency in 1971.
    - Lee, Gary, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9611)
      Interview. Lee was Tompkins County Republican chairman, 1969-1974. Interview begins at 4 minutes, 51 seconds.
    - Lefkowitz, Louis - Part 1, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9513)
      Interview. Lefkowitz was New York State Attorney General, 1957-1978, and the Republican New York City mayoral candidate in 1961. Lefkowitz interview ends at 74 minutes, 40 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with John Debbink until end. Debbink was a long-time employee at General Motors who headed the Delco Moraine division.
    - Lefkowitz, Louis - Part 2, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9612)
      Interview. Lefkowitz was New York State Attorney General, 1957-1978, and the Republican New York City mayoral candidate in 1961. Lefkowitz interview ends at 31 minutes, 15 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with unidentified individual discussing strategic planning at General Motors.
    - LeFrak, Samuel, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9613)
      Interview. LeFrak was a real estate investor who served on the New York State Traffic Safety Council and the Saratoga Springs Commission. Interview begins at 2 minutes, 32 minutes.
    - Lengyel, Henry, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9614)
      Interview. Lengyell was Jefferson County (NY) Republican Chair.
    - Lerner, Alfred D., and Kunzeman, Joseph, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9615)
      Interview. Lerner was a member of the New York State Assembly for parts of Queens County in the early 1960s, and Kunzeman was also a member of the Assembly for Queens County during the 1960s.
    - Levine, Louis, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9616)
      Interview. Levine was New York State Industrial Commissioner, 1966-1976. Levine interview ends at 62 minutes, 18 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Jim Cannon until end. Cannon was an aide to Nelson Rockefeller when he was Governor of New York and then Vice President.
    - Levitch and Lightfoot, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9617)
      Interview. Levitch and Lightfoot were lawyers who worked on the construction project of Empire State Plaza, also known as the South Mall, in Albany. Levitch and Lightfoot interview ends at 75 minutes, 10 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Ed Logue until end. Logue was an urban planner who oversaw numerous redevelopment projects across New York.
    - Lipset, Harvey, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9621)
      Interview. Lipset was a Democratic New York State Assemblyman, 1957-1968.
    - Lindsay, Franklin and Margot, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9619)
      Interview. Franklin Lindsay was a consultant who advised Nelson Rockefeller regarding the Open Skies program during Rockefeller's service in the Eisenhower administration as Special Assistant to the President. Margot Lindsay served on the Republicans for Progress group and the Draft Rockefeller movement in the 1968 Presidential campaign. Tape begins with interview with Franklin Lindsay until 61 minutes, 26 seconds. Tape then contains interview with Margot Lindsay until end.
    - Lindsay, John, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9620)
      Interview. Lindsay served in the U.S. House of Representatives, 1959-1965, and was mayor of New York, 1966 to 1973, during much of Nelson Rockefeller's tenure as Governor of New York. Lindsay was a Republican who switched to the Democratic party while serving as Mayor. Lindsay interview ends at 68 minutes, 58 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Ravi Batra until end. Batra is an economist, author, and professor. Interview focuses on topics covered in Batra's book "The Great Depression of 1990."
    - Livingston, Kathryn, 1982 June 17; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9622)
      Interview. Livingston was executive editor at Town and Country magazine.
    - Lockwood, John - Part 1, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9623A)
      Interview. Lockwood was legal counsel to the Rockefeller family. Also served as chair of the board of the New York Public Library.
    - Lockwood, John - Part 2, circa 1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9623B)
      Interview. Lockwood was legal counsel to the Rockefeller family. Also served as chairman of the New York Public Library.
    - Lodge, George, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9624)
      Interview. Lodge is the son of Henry Cabot Lodge, Jr. Lodge interview begins at 1 minute and ends at 17 minutes. Tape then contains partial interview with Sol Corbin until end. Corbin was Governor Nelson Rockefeller's top legal advisor.
    - Logue, Ed, 1982 May 11; Sound, 267 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9625)
      Interview. Logue was an urban planner who oversaw numerous redevelopment projects across New York.
      Audio becomes highly distorted and unintelligible at 140 minutes and becomes normal again at 185 minutes, 41 seconds.
    - Love, John, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9627)
      Interview. Love was governor of Colorado, 1963-1973. Beginning of the tape contains a conversation with Reich and a Rockefeller Archive Center archivist named Harold until 4 minutes, 43 seconds. Tape then contains interview with Love until 24 minutes, 27 seconds. Tape then contains partial interivew with Warren Weaver until end. Weaver was a reporter for the New York Times.
    - Lovelock, Bill, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9628)
      Interview. Lovelock was a detective lieutenant in the New York Police Department and served as a bodyguard for Governor Nelson Rockefeller. Was a detective lieutenant in the and served as a bodyguard for Governor Nelson Rockefeller.
    - Lumbard, Eliot, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9626)
      Interview. Tape begins with partial interivew with John Innes until 2 minutes, 45 seconds. Innes was a Republican county chairman. Tape then contains interview with Lumbard until end. Lumbard was Special Assistant Counsel for Law Enforcement to Governor Nelson Rockefeller, 1961 - 1967.
    - Lyden, Collins, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9629)
      Interview. Lyden was a campaign aide to Nelson Rockefeller.
    - Lynes, Russell, 1982 March 27; Sound, 81 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9630)
      Interview
      Tape is highly distorted throughout, making the interview unintelligible.
    - MacCrate, Robert, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9631)
      Interview. MacCrate was associate counsel (1959) and then counsel (1959-1962) to Governor Nelson Rockefeller.
    - Mackell, Thomas J., circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9632)
      Interview. MacKell was a New York state senator from Queens from 1955 to 1966, and then district attorney of Queens County from 1967 to 1973.
    - Mahoney, Dan, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9633)
      Interview. Mahoney helped found the New York Conservative Party in 1962.
    - Maiorana, Ronald, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9634)
      Interview. Maiorana was press secretary for Governor Nelson Rockefeller.
    - Maloney, Francis, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9635)
      Interview. Maloney was a law partner of John Mitchell, who introduced moral obligation bonds to Governor Nelson Rockefeller.
    - Marchi, John, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9636)
      Interview. Marchi was a Republican New York state senator from Staten Island.
    - Margiotta, Joseph, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9637)
      Interview. Margiotta was the New York State Assembly member from Uniondale, 1966 to 1976, and Nassau County (NY) Republican chair from 1968 to 1983. Margiotta interview ends at 99 minutes, 10 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Joseph Crangle until end. Crangle was Erie County (NY) Democratic chair and then New York State Democratic chair.
    - Marshall, Alton - Part 1, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9639A)
      Interview. Marshall was Secretary to the Governor; a 1968 Presidential campaign staffer; and President of Rockefeller Center, Inc.
    - Marshall, Alton - Part 2, circa 1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9639B)
      Interview. Marshall was Secretary to the Governor; a 1968 Presidential campaign staffer; and President of Rockefeller Center, Inc. Marshall interview ends at 34 minutes, 55 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with an unidentified individual until 94 minutes, 2 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview Marshall interview with Marshall until end.
    - Marshall, Alton - Part 3, circa 1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9639C)
    - Marshall, Alton - Part 4, circa 1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9639D)
      Interview. Marshall was Secretary to the Governor; a 1968 Presidential campaign staffer; and President of Rockefeller Center, Inc. Marshall interview ends at 17 minutes, 17 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Robert Purcell until 73 minutes, 53 seconds. Purcell was president of IBEC and a financial advisor to the Rockefeller family. Tape then contains interview with Marshall until end.
    - Marshall, Alton - Part 5, circa 1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9639E)
      Interview. Marshall was Secretary to the Governor; a 1968 Presidential campaign staffer; and President of Rockefeller Center, Inc. Marshall interview ends at 262 minutes, 4 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Bruce Gyory until end. Gyory was a political consultant.
    - Marshall, Alton - Part 6, circa 1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9639F)
      Interview. Marshall was Secretary to the Governor; a 1968 Presidential campaign staffer; and President of Rockefeller Center, Inc. Marshall interview ends at 118 minutes, 30 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Thomas MacKell until 187 minutes, 3 seconds. MacKell was a New York state senator, 1955-1966, and district attorney of Queens County, 1967-1973. Tape then contains interview with Marshall until end.
    - Marshall, Alton - Part 7, circa1980s; Sound, 94 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9640)
      Interview. Marshall was Secretary to the Governor; a 1968 Presidential campaign staffer; and President of Rockefeller Center, Inc. Marshall interview ends at 65 minutes, 58 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview Peter Ogden until end. Ogden was an architect who collaborated with Nelson Rockefeller and also worked on IBEC housing projects.
    - Martin, June, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9641)
      Interview. Martin was a campaign aide to Nelson Rockefeller.
    - Martindale, Steven, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9642)
      Interview. Martindale was a campaign aide to Nelson Rockefeller.
    - Massolo, Arthur, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9644)
      Interview. Massolo was a reporter for the New York Post and then gubernatorial aide to Nelson Rockefeller.
    - Mathias, Charles, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9645)
      Interview. Mathias was a Republican politician from Maryland who served in the U.S. House of Representatives, 1961-1969, and the U.S. Senate, 1969-1987. Mathias interview ends at 63 minutes, 54 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Sandy Morhouse until end. Morhouse was the son of L. Judson Morhouse, who was Republican state chairman of New York.
    - McCrary, Tex, 1982 February 21; Sound, 189 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9646)
      Interview. McCrary was a radio and television personality, public relations specialist, and advisor to Nelson Rockefeller during the 1958 New York gubernatorial campaign. McCrary interview ends at 47 minutes, 59 seconds. Tape then contains interview with Rufus Miles until 93 minutes, 38 seconds. Miles worked at the Department of Health, Education, and Welfare while Nelson Rockefeller was the department's under-secretary. Tape then contains interview with McCrary until end, although the interview is unintelligible.
      Audio is highly distorted and unintelligible from 94 minutes until end.
    - McCray, Porter, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9647)
      Interview. McCrary worked with Nelson Rockefeller when Rockefeller was the Coordinator of Inter-American Affairs and at the Museum of Modern Art while Rockefeller was the museum's chairman.
    - McEneny, John J., circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9648)
      Interview. McEneny was head of the human resources department under Albany Mayor Erastus Corning. Tape begins with interview with unidentified individual until 10 minutes, 40 seconds
    - McEwen, Robert, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9649)
      Interview. McEwen was a Republican New York State senator, 1954-1964, and a member of the U.S. House of Representatives, 1965-1981.
    - McGovern, Joseph, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9650)
      Interview. McGovern was a bond attorney who worked on the financing of the construction of the Empire State Plaza in Albany.
    - McKee, Jean, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9651)
      Interview. McKee was a gubernatorial aide to Nelson Rockefeller.
    - McWhorter, Charles, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9652)
      Interview. McWhorter was a lawyer and aide to Richard Nixon.
    - Melich, Tanya, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9653)
      Interview. Melich was an aide to Governor Nelson Rockefeller. Melich interview ends at 157 minutes, 35 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with unidentified individual until end.
    - Miller, Alan, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9654)
      Interview. Miller was New York State Commissioner of Mental Hygiene, 1966-1975.
    - Miller, Dorothy - Part 1, 1982 November 23; Sound, 311 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9655A)
      Interview. Miller was a curator at the Museum of Modern Art and a consulatant and curator for numerous art projects for the Rockefeller family. Miller interview ends at 198 minutes, 3 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with investment banker Michel David-Weil until 208 minutes. Tape then contains no content until interview with Miller and an unidentified woman begins at 217 minutes, 28 seconds and lasts until the end of the tape.
      Speed becomes too fast at 206 minutes, and audio eventually becomes unintelligble from 208 minutes until 214 minutes, 20 seconds.
    - Miller, Dorotthy - Part 2, 1982 November 23?; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9655B)
      Interview.
    - Miller, Irwin, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9656)
      Interview. Miller was chair of the Rockefeller for President Commmittee during the 1968 presidential campaign. Interview with Miller begins at 2 minutes, 15 seconds and ends at 36 minutes, 40 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Milton Gwirtzman until end. Gwirtzman was an advisor and speech writer for John, Bobby, and Edward Kennedy.
    - Mitchell, Donna, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9657)
      Interview. Mitchell was a long-time associate of Nelson Rockefeller, beginning with his service in the Eisenhower administration on the committee to reorganize the federal government (PACGO/SCOGO) and then the newly created Department of Health, Education, and Welfare. Mitchell interview ends at 118 minutes, 48 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Edward Kresky until end. Kresky was a gubernatorial aide to Nelson Rockefeller.
    - Mitrovich, George, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9658)
      Interview. Mitrovich was press secretary for U.S. Senator Charles Goodell, who was apppointed by Governor Nelson Rockefeller to fill the seat after Senator Robert F. Kennedy's assassination in 1968. Interview was conducted by phone rather than in person. Mitrovich interview ends at 82 minutes, 7 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Edward Cain until end. Cain was chair of the Genesee County Republican Committee.
    - Moore, Beth, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9659)
      Interview. Moore was chairman of the board of the State University of New York and friend of Nelson Rockefeller.
    - Moore, Jonathan, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9660)
      Interview. During the 1968 Republican presidential primaries, Moore was foreign policy advisor to Michigan Governor George Romney and then foreign policy advisor to Governor Nelson Rockefeller after Romney dropped out of the campaign.
    - Moreira Salles, Walther, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9729)
      Interview. Moreira Salles was a Brazilian banker and philanthropist who was an investor in Nelson Rockefeller's International Basic Economy Corporation (IBEC). He was also a friend of David Rockefeller.
    - Morgenthau, Robert, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9661)
      Interview. Morgenthau was the 1962 Democratic nominee for Governor of New York.
    - Morhouse, Sandy, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9662)
      Interview. Morhouse was the son of L. Judson Morhouse, who was Republican state chairman of New York.
    - Morrison, Edward, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9663)
      Interview. Morrison was Liberal Party of New York leader.
    - Mottahedeh, Mildred, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9664)
      Interview. Mottahedeh was a friend of Nelson Rockefeller and co-founded a company that produced porcelain reproductions for several United States presidents and museums. Mottahedeh interview ends at 30 minutes, 42 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Robert Stone until end. Stone served as Executive Deputy Secretary of State and then Deputy Commissioner of General Services under Governor Nelson Rockefeller.
    - Moylan, Neal, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9665)
      Interview. Moylan was New York State Commerce Commissioner.
    - Moynihan, Daniel Patrick, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9666)
      Interview. Moynihan was a member of New York Governor Averell Harriman's staff. He also served in the administrations of Presidents John F. Kennedy, Lyndon Johnson, Richard Nixon, and Gerald Ford before representing New York in the United States Senate, 1977-2001. Moynihan interview ends at 57 minutes, 11 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Daniel Button until 104 minutes, 18 seconds. Button was assistant to the president of the State University of New York, 1952-1958; executive editor of the Albany Times Union newspaper, 1960-1966; and a Republican member of the United States House of Representatvies, 1967-1971. Tape then contintues with interview with Moynihan until 114 minutes, 6 seconds. Tape then contains two separate partial interviews with unidentified individuals until end.
    - Murray, J. Lawrence, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9668)
      Interview. Murray worked for New York politician Frank Moore in various capacities during the 1950s and 1960s and served as acting chief administrative officer of the State University of New York, 1963-1964. Murray interview ends at 150 minutes, 49 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with George Gilder until end. Gilder was a speechwriter for Nelson Rockefeller.
    - Musicus, Milton, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9669)
      Interview. Musicus served Governor Nelson Rockefeller as Assistant Secretary for Administration; later served on staff of Mayor John Lindsay. Musicus interview ends at 74 minutes, 20 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Alexander Lankler until end. Lankler was a campaign aide to Governor Rockefeller.
  - N-P, 2.6
    - Nathan, Dick, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9670)
      Interview. Nathan was an ddvisor to Governor Nelson Rockefeller and, later, director of the Rockefeller Institute of Government.
    - Neuberger, Roy, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9671)
      Interview. Neuberger was a financier, philanthropist, and art collector who knew Governor Nelson Rockefeller throught their mutual love of modern art. Neuberger interview ends at 76 minutes, 4 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Peter Cohen. Cohen was CEO of Shearson Lehman Brothers. The Cohen interview is not connected to Reich's Rockefeller book.
    - Newman, Bernard - Part 1, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9672A)
      Interview. Newman was was counsel to the New York State Republican Party and was appointed to the New York State Supreme Court by Governor Nelson Rockefeller.